A Guide to the Robert Lewis Dabney Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #38-219
Robert Lewis Dabney Papers 1834-1910
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
38-219
ca. 1000 items
Dr. Charles W. Dabney
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The papers were gifts to the University of Virginia Library from Dr. Charles W. Dabney in 1937 (#38-219) and 1939 (#660).
Scope and Content
Papers of, and relating to, Robert Lewis Dabney(1820-1898). Born in Louisa County, Virginia, Dabney was a student at Hampden-Sidney College and then at the University of Virginia where he graduated with the M.A. degree, and finally at Union Theological Seminary in Richmond, Virginia, where he graduated in 1846. He became a Presbyterian clergyman and was a professor at Union Theological Seminary from 1853 until 1883, except for the years of the Civil War when he served as a chaplain in the Confederate army until becoming chief of staff to General Thomas J. Jackson in 1862. Dabney concluded his life's work as a professor at the University of Texas, 1883-1898.
The bulk of the collection consists of family letters from Dabney to his mother, Elizabeth Dabney, his brother, Charles William Dabney, and occasionally to his wife or other relatives; some of the correspondence concerns business of the Presbyterian Church. A number of the letters were written during Dabney's residence at Hampden-Sidney College and the University of Virginia; among the latter is an account of the the trial of Joseph G. Semmes, the student accused of killing Law Professor John A. G. Davis in 1840. The collection also includes speeches written in Dabney's student days, an autobiographical account extending to the early 1890's, and numerous photostatic copies of letters and papers by or concerning General Thomas J. Jackson used by Dabney in his biography of Jackson. The collection also includes a large number of letters written in 1898 to and from Dabney's sons concerning the rights to Dabney's writings, new editions, and a biography of Dabney by Professor Thomas Cary Johnson of Union Theological Seminary.
Container List
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1834 Oct 19; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1835 Oct 4; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Jun 4; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Jun 14; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Jun 23; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Jun 28; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1836 Jul 5; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Jul 23; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Aug 5; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1836 Aug 5; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Aug 13; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Aug 20; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Sep 2; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1836 Sep 8; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Sep 10; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Sep 24; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Nov 6; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1836 Nov 9; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Essay on Robert Fulton, 1836; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: "On the Death of Madison", 1836; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Oration on the humility of man, 1837 Jan 15; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: "On the Comparative Excellence of Ancient and Modern Architecture", 1837 Jan 31; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Oration on Venice, 1837 Feb 14; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: "Oration on the Emigration of Foreigners to Our Country", 1837 Feb 26; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: "Composition: A Comparison Between Epaminodas and Washington", 1837 Jun 20; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Address to Philanthropic Society, Hampden-Sidney, 1837 Jul; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Speech on Superstition, ca. 1837; AMS (Box Box 1)
- "College Circular" for Robert Lewis Dabney, 1837 Sep 25; ADS (Box Box 1)
- D.L. Carroll to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Oct 1; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Jan 8; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1837 Jan 21; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Jan 23; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Feb 3; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1837 Feb 20; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Feb 28; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1837 Mar 16; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Mar 19; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Mar 30; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Jun 3; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Jun 25; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1837 Jul 6; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Jul 10; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1837 Aug 1; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Sep 1; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1837 Sep 18; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 Jan 4; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1840 Jan 16; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 Jan 28; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 Jan 31; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 Feb 6; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1840 Mar 2; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1840 Mar 12; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to George Woodson Payne, Jr., 1840 Mar 18; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1840 Apr 22; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 May 8; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 Jun 18; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840? Aug 29; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1840 Oct 13; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1840 Oct 20; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 Oct 25; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1840 Nov 13; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1840 Nov 15; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1840 Dec 7; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 Dec 7 [?]; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1840 Dec 31; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: "Grammatica Latina in usum sororis", ca. 1840; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney:"Questions on Turner's Chemistry", ca. 1840; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Notes on Political Economy, 1840-1841; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Notes on Moral Philosophy, 1840-1841; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: "Claims of the Ancient Literature", 1840 Mar; AMs (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Address: "The Great West", 1840 Nov; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1841 Feb 23; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841 Feb 23; ALS (Box Box 1)
- newspaper article w/ink signature "C. W. Dabney", 1841 Mar 4; Clipping (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841? Mar 11; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841 Apr 28; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1841 May 8; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841 May 27; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: "Comparative Excellence of Our Authors", 1841 May; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1841 Jun 13; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841 Sep 3; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1841 Sep 22; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841 Sep 25; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841 Nov 6; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Miss Betty Dabney, 1841 Nov 20; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Miss Betty Dabney, 1841 Nov 30; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1841 Dec 15; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841 Dec 23; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Miss Betty Dabney, ca. 1841; ALS (Box Box 1)
- R. L. and George Francis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1841[?]; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mr. George Francis Dabney, 1842 Jan 11; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, [1842] Jan 24; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1842 Feb 7; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to George Woodson Payne, Jr., 1842 Feb 15; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to George Francis Dabney, 1842 Mar 15; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1842 Jun 9; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1842 Jun 27; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: "Temperance", 1842 [Spring]; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: [on the national economy], 1842 [Spring]; AMS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: [improving the grounds of U.Va.], 1842; AMs (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1844 Jan 29; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1844? Aug 17; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1844 Nov 12; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1844 Nov 22; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1844 Dec 16; ALS (Box Box 1)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1845 Feb 4; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1845 Feb 6; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to George Francis Dabney, 1845 Mar 16; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1845 Jun 7; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1845 Jun 12; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1845 Jul 8; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1845 Aug 2; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to George Woodson Payne, Jr., 1845 Aug 6; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1845 Dec 4; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1845 Dec 14; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Miss E. T. Dabney, [1845] Dec 18; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1845 Dec 29; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to George Francis Dabney, 1846 Feb 18; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1846 Feb 5; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1846 Feb 21; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1846 Apr 14; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1846 Sep 5; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1846 Sep 14; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1846 Sep 17; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1847 Apr 17; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1847 Jul 16; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1847 Aug 26; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1847 Oct 7; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1847 Dec 29; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1848 Jan 3; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1848 Jan 17; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1848 Feb 3; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1848 Mar 7; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1848 May 1; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1848 May 1; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1848 May 5; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1848 May 24; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1848 Jun 2; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1848 Sep 1; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1848 Nov 24; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1848 Dec 4; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Jan 9; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1849 Feb 6; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Feb 20; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Feb 26; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1849 Mar 8; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1849 Apr 18; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Apr 19; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1849 May 1; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1849 Jun 13; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Jul 9; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Jul 20; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1849 Jul 30; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Aug 13; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1849 Oct 3; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Oct 8; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1849 Nov 15; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1849 Dec 31; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Syllabus of Butler's Analogy, 1850; AMs (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1850 Feb 18; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1850 Apr 3; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1850 Apr 3; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1850 Apr 29; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1850 Jun 8; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Miss Betty Dabney, 1850 Jul 6; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1850 Jul 29; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1850 Sep 23; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1850 Sep 30; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1851 Jan 15; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1851 Mar 6; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1851 Jun 21; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1851 Aug 4; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1851 Sep 4; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1851 Sep 20; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1851 Oct 5; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1851 Oct 21; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Luther Emerson to Robert Lewis Dabney, 1851 Nov 15; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mr. J. Cross, 1851 Nov 21; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1852 Jan 7; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to M. D. Hoge, 1852 Jan 28; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1852 Feb 4; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1852 Mar 16; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1852 Apr 30; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1852 Jun 28; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1852 Jun 30; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to [?], 1852 Jun 21; L [copy] (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: Address to Union Theological Seminary, 1853 Jun 2; AMs (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Miss Betty Dabney, 1853 Mar 4; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1853 Apr 5; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1853 May 24; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1853 Oct 10; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1853 Nov 25; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1854 Mar 23; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1854 Apr 24; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. O. Phelps Brown, 1854 Nov 6; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1855 Jan 20; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1855 Mar 17; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1855 Jun 19; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1855 Jun 19; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1855 Sep 16; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to M. D. Hoge, 1855 Nov 7; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1855 Nov 15; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1855 Dec 12; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1855 Dec 23; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1856 Jan 13; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1856 Feb 15; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1856 Mar 27; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1856 May 12; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1856 May 19; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1856 May 23; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1856 May 29; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1856 Aug 4; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1856 Oct 10; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1856 Oct 26; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1857 Jan 6; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1857 Jan 20; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1857 Apr 7; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1857 Jul 3; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1857 Sep 3; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1857 Nov 28; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1857 Dec 2; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. McGuffey, 1857 Dec 24; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1857 Dec 25; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858[?]; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1858 Jan 28; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1858 Feb 2; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1858 Feb 17; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to M. D. Hoge, 1858 Mar; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 May 25; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 Jun; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 Jun 28; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 Jul 5; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 Jul 12; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to M. D. Hoge, 1858 Jul 15; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 Jul 19; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 Jul 19; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 Aug 13; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1858 Aug 18; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1858 Aug 23; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1858 Aug 23; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1858 Sep 2; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Miss Betty Dabney, 1858 Oct 18; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1858 Oct 21; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1858 Dec 13; ALS (Box Box 2)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1859 Jan 5; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1859 Feb 9; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1859 Feb 22; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to H. G. Guthrie, 1859 Feb 26; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to H. G. Guthrie, 1859 Apr 19; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1859 Jun 20; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1859 Jul 21; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Clerk of the County Court of Louisa, 1859 Aug 8; ANS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1859 Aug 16; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his wife, 1859 Aug 20; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, 1859 Nov 22; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Israel P. Warren, 1859 Dec 13; L [copy] (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1859 Dec 23; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1859 Dec 24; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Israel P. Warren to Robert Lewis Dabney, 1859 Dec 26; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to H. G. Guthrie, 1859 Dec 29; ALS (Box Box 3)
- order for forage for Robert Lewis Dabney's horse, 1861; ANS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to T. J. Jackson, 1863 Mar 5; ALS (Box Box 3)
- T. J. Jackson to Gen. R. E. Lee, 1863 May 2; L [copy] (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney, "Advertisement to the Reader" of his defense of slavery in the Confederacy, 1864 Oct 29; AMS (Box Box 3)
- Verse of Robert Lewis Dabney, 1870-86?; 2 AMs, 1 TMs (Box Box 3)
- Francis H. Smith to Robert Lewis Dabney, 1882 Jul 15; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Tributes to Robert E. Lee from the Southern Historical Society Papers, 1889; 3 AMs, 2 TMs (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney: article on U.S. party politics written for London Quarterly Review, 1881; AMs (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. Joseph D. Eggleston, 1890 Apr 7; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to George [Woodson Payne], 1890 Jun 7; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. Joseph D. Eggleston, 1890 Sep 13; ALS (Box Box 3)
- S. B. Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1890 Sep 20; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1891 Jan 20; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1891 Jan 21; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1891 Mar 14; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1891 Mar 31; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1891 Apr 20; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Sarah Lane, 1892 May 29; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Mrs. Anne E. Payne, 1892 Oct 1; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1892 Oct 11; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1892 Oct 20; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1892 Oct 29; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. C. R. Vaughan, 1892 Nov 7; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Dr. J. D. Eggleston, 1892 Dec 17; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1893 Jan 21; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1893 Feb 4; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to his son, 1893 Feb 4; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to M. D. Hoge, 1893 Feb 20; L [copy] (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1893 Feb 25; ALS (Box Box 3)
- Robert Lewis Dabney to Charles W. Dabney, 1893 Mar 24; ALS (Box Box 3)